Go to extremes. As an exercise, we have people put on a caricature of an American
accent, and generally it's quite accurate. They're reluctant, however, to use it
because of the inherent mockery involved. It's okay, I can assure you that Americans
won't even notice when you're putting on a super heavy American accent. They'll just
think your English got better. Your family and friends may react negatively and make
fun of your nascent attempts to modify your speech. way you are. They may think
that your accent is cute. They may think that if you change how you talk, you may
change who you are. The bottom line is that you'll sound different and they may
not like it. We recommend practicing on strangers. They don't have a baseline and
can accept you at face value. At this point, it may be hard for you to conceive
how differently you'll be treated. A lot of Americans, I regret to say, turn off
when they hear a foreign accent or are less than kind. Since we can't change all
of them, we can make a small change in you.